他们是一支与众不同的军队…
They are an army unlike any other...
在星际之间遨游 向他们的受允之地
crusading across the stars toward a place called UnderVerse,
黑暗星际前进
their promised land...
一个黑暗笼罩的新世界
a constellation of dark new worlds.
他们被称作死亡使者
Necromongers, they're called.
如果你不归顺他们 就会被杀
And if they can not convert you, they will kill you.
领导他们的就是马歇尔王
Leading them, the Lord Marshal.
他独自到星际之门朝圣
He alone has made a pilgrimage to the gates of the UnderVerse...
回来时完全变了样
and returned a different being.
变得更强大 更陌生了
Stronger. Stranger.
一半是人 另一半是
Half alive and half...
其他什么…
something else.
如果我们想要生存 就必须找到新的平衡
If we are to survive, a new balance must be found.
一般情况 正义总能战胜邪恶
In normal times, evil would be fought by good.
但现在…
But in times like these, well,
需要另一种邪恶来制止
it should be fought by another kind of evil.
《星际传奇2》
(UV星系 6号星球)
别逃 稳住 我们来了
Linin' him up for you. Port-side shot comin' up. Steady. Here we go.
稳住
Steady.
发射 发射
Take it. Take it!
开火
Take the shot!
该死 托姆斯 没路了
Shit! Toombs, we're runnin' out of road!
闭嘴 我知道 再来
Shut up! I got it! Again!
现在
Now!
托姆斯
Toombs!
瑞迪
Riddick.
托姆斯 我不清楚 看上去太窄了
I don't know, Toombs. Looks kind of tight.
我可不管 这可是报酬最高的一次
Not where I'm sittin'. This is the biggest payday ever,
别磨蹭了 快点进去
So throw on a fresh pair of panties. Let's get this right.
左舷3米 右舷1.5米
Three meters clearance port-side. One and a half meters starboard.
当心隘口
We got a choke point comin'up.
该死的 这到底是什么？
What the shit was that?
泰格斯 你看见瑞迪了吗？
Tags, you got eyes on Riddick?
泰格斯？
Tags?
上帝
Jesus.
他一下子干了两个人 而我都还没看见他
He just ghosted two guys, and I never even saw him.
托姆斯 你认为怎样好？也许 我们应该…
What do you think, Toombs? I mean, maybe we ought to just...
我想现在你是我的新枪手
I think you're my new gunner.
拿上枪
Grab a Gat.
这次在他上面
Stay on top of him this time.
你犯了三个错误
You made three mistakes.
第一 你接了这个活
First, you took the job.
第二 你来得太轻率
Second, you came light.
一支四个人的队伍来抓我？太小看我了
A four-man crew for me? Fuckin' insulting.
但是你犯的最严重的错误是…
But the worst mistake you made...
空弹匣
Empty gun rack.
- 我的头现在值多少？- 一百万
- What's the bounty on my head?  - One mil.
- 一百五十万  - 谁付你这一百五十万？
- One-point-five.  - What slam pays 1.5 for a convict?
一个秘密组织
Private party.
嘿 嘿 嘿 朋友 别紧张 没有姓名
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Guy, guy! Easy! Anonymous.
- 单子上是这样写的  - 哪个星球？
- That's what the sheet said.  - What planet?
希里奥·帕莱姆
Helion Prime.
哇 你要去哪 赏金猎人？最后一个问题
Whoa. Where you goin'? Last question.
你最好好好回答
And you better get this one right, merc.
这艘飞船是谁的？
Whose ship is this?
我的？
Mine?
他们是为我而来
Knew they'd come for me.
他们花了五年时间 但是我知道
Took'em five years, but I knew.
你不能指望这些赏金猎人 有尊严 有原则
You don't expect these mercs to have any honor, any code.
但是这次的悬赏来自一位圣人
But this new bounty from a holy man,
一个我曾经救过的人
a guy whose neck I saved...
嗯 学到一课
Well, lesson learned.
没有"朋友"这个词
No such word as "friend."
让别人接近自己太近 总没好下场
Can only end bad when you let someone get too close.
对他们不好
Bad for them.
所以现在是回到所有光明的 一切我憎恨的那里
So now it's back to all the brightness... and everything I hate.
不知她会否在那儿
Wonder if she'll be there.
(火成星系 烈焰星)
你像只动物 我要把你关起来
Act like an animal and I'm gonna slot you up like one.
这家伙总是惹麻烦
This one is always in trouble.
我知道 我闻出来了
I knew it! I smell it.
进去
Get in there!
别吵
Can we shut the goddamn noise?
在低温休眠状态下人脑是停止活动的
They say most of your brain shuts down in cryosleep.
低温休眠下大脑是停止的
Brain shuts down in cryosleep.
- 除了原始的一面  - 除了原始的一面
- All but the primitive side.  - All but the primitive side.
动物的一面
The animal side.
复仇星人的一面
All but the Furyan side.
我们中的一些人还记得 曾经发生在复仇星上的罪行
Some of us still remember the true crime that happened here on Furya.
当你一旦醒来…
And once you wake...
真正醒来…
truly wake...
你也会记得
you'll remember too.
帕莱姆警戒等级4
Helion Prime is on alert condition four.
未识别飞船 请跟我到六号发射台接受安全检查
Unrecognized craft. You need to follow me to Spaceport Six for security inspections.
嘿 听到吗？
Hey! Do you hear me?
立即跟我到六号发射台
Follow me to Spaceport Six now!
(希里奥星系 希里奥 帕莱姆星)
伊曼 为我们祈祷
Imam, pray for us.
确认了 是的 两季后
It was confirmed two seasons back. Yes.
他们就要来了 我们是下一个吗？
They're coming here. I mean, are we next?
要开战了…
Militants storm...
是 到那时躲到地下掩体里
Yes. But going to the underground shelters if it happens...
你说的对 我也这么想
You're right. That's what I thought too.
你准备留下还是离开？
Are you staying or leaving?
都结束了 都结束了
It's the end of everything. Everything!
哦 我的邻居… 半条街都空了
Well, my neighbors... Half my street is gone.
我们该怎么办？我不知道 我不知道
What are we gonna do? I don't know. I don't know.
人们叫他们 魔鬼胡德
Hood of the devil. That's what someone called 'em.
他们？他们是谁？新人种？
Them? Who is them? Some kind of new creature...
胡说八道 全是废话
This is nonsense. It's all nonsense.
他们高得可以触到云
So tall that it touches the clouds.
雕像周围一点东西都没有 什么都没有
And there's nothing around this statue, this colossus. Nothing left.
那是他们的标志
It's their calling card.
你知不知道所有的门都锁上了？
Did you know all your doors were locked?
五年前
Five years ago,
我从那个星球带走了两个人
I took two people off that planet...
一个孩子 杰克 谁都认为是个男孩
A kid, Jack, who everyone else thought was a boy
和一位圣人…
and a holy man...
寻找新麦加的圣人
searching for New Mecca.
你的妻子…
Your wife...
她在洗澡
She's in the shower.
我告诉了一个男人
I told one man...
我要去的地方
where I might go.
我把信任给了他
I showed trust to one man.
伊曼 我是不是错了？
Did I make a mistake, Imam?
答案不是那么简单的
There is no simple answer.
所有说过的话 都是为了给我们一个机会
Whatever was said was meant to give us a chance...
一个战斗的机会
a fighting chance.
如果不是有侵略的威胁 我永远不会背叛你
Were it not for the threat of invasion, I never would have betrayed you.
我向你保证 瑞迪 瑞迪
I give you my word, Riddick. Riddick!
瑞迪
Riddick!
还有个女儿…
And a daughter...
- 不  - 她的名字是…
- No!  - Whose name would be...
如果你对我有意见 找我
If you have issue with me, you let it be with me.
- 你不需要知道她们的名字  - 西扎
- You need not know their names.  - Ziza.
我的名字是西扎
My name is Ziza.
西扎
Ziza.
- 可爱的孩子  - 你真的杀过怪物吗？
- Cute kid.  - Did you really kill monsters?
那些想杀害我父亲的怪物？
The ones that were gonna hurt my father?
那些是她晚上睡觉前听的故事
Such are our bedtime stories.
走吧 西扎 睡觉去
Go, Ziza. Go on!
我要杀了谁才能摘掉挂在我头上的悬赏？
So now who do I have to kill to get this payday off my head?
据说慧星过后
It is said the comet always precedes them...
就是世界末日
these world-enders.
那些煤袋区域的行星都不见了
The Coal sack planets are gone.
800万居民失踪
Eight million settlers missing.
整个天鹰座也消失了
The entire Aquiline System is gone too.
希里奥 帕莱姆和附近的其他星球分享阳光
Helicon Prime shares its sunlight with all worlds nearby.
如果我们完了 他们也完了
If we fall, they fall.
如果那样的话
And after that...
天哪 我怎么救我的家人？
My God, how do I save my family?
你听到我说的了吗？
Have you heard anything I've said?
你说整个宇宙都将毁灭
You said it's all circling the drain... the whole universe.
- 对吗？- 对
- Right?  - That's right.
终有一日要终结
Had to end sometime.
你要的人现在就在这里
The one you want is now here.
这是谁的咽喉？
And whose throat is this?
如果你割了我的喉咙 我就没有办法废除你的悬赏令
If you cut my throat, I'll not be able to rescind the offer that brought you here.
也不能告诉你为什么非要你到这里来
Nor tell you why it's so vital that you did come.
悬赏取消 刀子才会拿开
The blade comes off when the bounty comes off.
这位是艾尔伦 来自元素族的使节
This is Aereon, an envoy from the Elemental race.
她对你没有恶意
She means you no harm.
没有几个人能在死亡使者 手底下逃生还能泄露他们的秘密
There are very few of us who have met a Necromonger and lived to speak of it.
我既然选择开口 你就应该听我说
So when I choose to speak of it, you should choose to listen.
死亡使者
Necromonger.
他们的名字就是顺我者昌 逆我者亡 直到最后一个人
It is the name that will convert or kill every last human life...
除非宇宙能重拾平衡
unless the universe can rebalance itself.
也许你该假装在谈话
Maybe you should pretend like you're talkin' to someone
比如和一位有教养的罪犯
educated in the penal system.
事实上 用不着假装
In fact, don't pretend.
平衡是所有元素的一切
Balance is everything to elementals.
水之于火 泥土之于空气
Water to fire. Earth to air.
有33对不同的描述
We have 33 different words for it.
现在我们只有时间来谈谈平衡的 两个对立面
But now we have only time to speak of the balance of opposites.
有个传说 瑞迪 关于年轻的复仇星人男性
There is a story, Riddick, of young male Furyans...
出生时被绞死
strangled at birth...
用他们自己的脐带绞死
strangled with their own cords.
当艾尔伦把这个故事告诉希里奥首领的时候
When Aereon told this story to the Helion leaders,
我对她提到了你
I told her of you.
你对你童年时候的事情知道多少？
What do you know of your early years?
你还记得你的家乡吗？
Do you remember your home world?
- 在哪里？- 你遇到过其他同类吗？
- Where it was?  - Have you met any others?
像你一样的同类
Others like yourself.
我一个就够他们受了
Sister, they don't know what to do with just one of me.
开门
Open up in there!
- 退后  - 开门
- Stand back!  - Open up!
- 他们在搜查  - 嘘
- They are searching houses!  - Shh!
他们在找一个今天到这里的男人 说他可能是个间谍
They look for a man who came here today. They think he might be a spy.
- 间谍？- 有人今天看见他来这里吗？
- A spy?  - Did someone see him come here today?
- 有吗？- 纳姜 住手
- Did they?  - Lajjun, stop!
- 我们确信他就在这里  - 我会把他们打发走 请等一会
- We're sure he's in there!  - I will send them away. But wait one minute, please.
为了拯救世界 能再等一会吗？
Will you wait one minute to save worlds?
这不是我的战争
Not my fight.
那么 你打算弃我们于不顾
So, you will leave us to our fate,
就象你弃她于不顾一样
just like you did her.
撞开
Break it down!
抓住他
Get him!
来吧 我们把他们打发走
Come. Let us try to send them away.
- 快 快点  - 走开
- Move it. Come on.  - Leave us alone!
这里没有人
There is no one here!
你们不明白 他能帮助我们 他能帮助我们
You don't understand. He can help us! He can help us!
上
Go!
你们不害怕黑暗 是吗？
You're not afraid of the dark, are you?
- 抓住他  - 他在哪儿？
- Get him!  - Where is he?
在那边
In there!
你提到她
You mentioned her.
她 呃
She, uh...
她去找你
She went looking for you.
有人死了 她被关进了监狱
People died. She went to prison.
我 我不记得在哪里了
I...I don't remember where.
但那个地方很热 在地面根本无法存活
But it was a world so hot you not survive on the surface.
烈焰星 小杰克
Crematoria. Young Jack.
她把你当作她的大哥哥
She thought of you as her older brother.
- 她崇拜你  - 你要好好照看好她
- She worshipped you.  - You were supposed to watch her.
她永远都不会原谅你
She never forgive you...
你在她最需要你的时候离开她…
for leaving just when she needed you most.
她应该离我远点 你们也是
She needed to stay away from me. You all do.
瑞迪
Riddick.
你会阻止新的怪兽吗？
Are you gonna stop the new monsters now?
复仇星人 永不低头
Furyans. Defiant to the end.
不 不
No, no.
我们去庇护所
We go to the shelter.
就我们自己去
We take only ourselves.
靠紧我
Stay close.
不
No!
指挥官们 让所有小队马上起飞
Flight leaders, get all squads off the ground now.
无法起飞
We have heavy inbound.
跟着我
Follow me in!
下一个庇护所 这边
The next shelter. This way!
耶
Yeah!
喔
Whoo-hoo!
我看看是否安全
I'll see if it's safe.
- 退后  - 来吧 西扎
- Stay back!  - Come, Ziza.
来吧
Come!
你跟着我吗？
You following me?
纳姜 西扎
Lajjun and Ziza!
- 等结束再走  - 让我走 我必须找到我的家人
- When it's over.  - Let me go. I must get to my family!
等结束了
When it's over.
我借了条船
I borrowed a ship.
你可以一起上船 如果你不介意我是个犯人
You can ride along, if you don't mind riding with a convict.
谢谢你 但是得先把家人送到对岸
I thank you, but I must get my family across the river.
运气好的话能帮他们找到一个庇护所
God willing, there is still a shelter I can get them...
上帝自有安排
I'm sure God has his tricks,
但若说谁能逃离这里
but getting out of places no one else can,
那非我莫属
that's one of mine.
我们去接你的家人
Let's get your family.
啊
Aah!
进去
In here.
Get in.
嘘
Shh.
- 伊曼  - 别跟着我
- Imam!  - Don't follow me.
我会有来世
There will be an afterlife for me.
你呢？
Will there be for you?
我们去补充一下兵员
Let's go replenish the ranks.
王朝的灭亡
Never fails to inspire, does it?
永远都会给你灵感 是吗？
Each time a dynasty falls.
记住你的位置 瓦寇夫人
Remember your place, Dame Vaako.
我的位置就在你旁边 亲爱的丈夫
My place is at your side, dear husband.
从这里直到暗黑星际
From here till UnderVerse come.
在这个宇宙
In this 'verse,
生命是和自然状态站在对立面的
life is antagonistic to the natural state.
这里 有不同种族的人类
Here, humans in all their various races...
战争不断的爆发
are a spontaneous outbreak...
这是无法控制的错误
an unguided mistake.
我们的目的…
Our purpose...
就是要纠正这个错误
is to correct that mistake.
因为还有另一个宇宙
Because there is another 'verse...
在那里生命受到接纳和珍惜
a 'verse where life is welcomed and cherished.
迷人 常新 那儿就是暗黑星际
A ravishing, ever-newplace called UnderVerse.
但是通往星际之路…
But the road to that 'verse...
要穿过星际之门
crosses over the threshold.
星际之门 带我们去星际之门
Threshold! Take us to the threshold!
你们称之为… 死亡
What you call... death.
所以在这个星球 生命必须净化
So it is this 'verse that must be cleansed of life,
这样暗黑星际才能繁荣昌盛
so that UnderVerse can populate and prosper.
看看你们周围 大厅里的每位死亡使者
Look around you. Every Necromonger in this hall,
一夜之间摧毁了你们防线的兵团里的每位死亡使者
every one of the Legion Vast that just swept aside your defenses in one night...
曾和你们一样
was once like you.
一样脆弱
Fought as feebly as you.
现在的每一位死亡使者
Every Necromonger that lives today...
都是皈依者
is a convert.
- 我们不会改变信仰  - 我们都得到了新生
- There'll be no conversions!  - We all began as something else!
当我第一次听到的时候 也很难接受
It was hard for me to accept, too, when I first heard these words.
但我改变了
But I changed.
我让他们带走了我的痛苦
I let them take away my pain.
- 你背叛了自己的信仰  - 当你意识到
- You betrayed your faith!  - Just as you will change...
只有接受死亡使者命运的人 才能通过星际之门时
when you realize that the threshold to the UnderVerse will be crossed...
你就会改变了
only by those who have embraced the Necromonger faith.
那时你们会立刻跪下来
For those of you who will right now...
要求净化
drop to your knees and ask to be purified.
- 我们不会背弃信仰  - 这里的所有人都不会
- We will not renounce our faith!  - No one here will do what you ask.
这是不可想像的
It is unthinkable!
这是一个多种族 多信仰的星球
This is a world of many peoples, many religions!
我们不能 也不会改变自己的信仰
And we simply cannot and will not be converted!
那我就拿走你的灵魂
Then I'll take your soul.
加入他
Join him...
还是加入我
or join me.
这是你唯一的机会
This is your one chance.
听从马歇尔王的命令跪下
Take the Lord Marshal's offer and bow.
我不向任何人下跪
I bow to no man.
他不是人
He's not a man.
他是见到过暗黑星际的半神
He's the holy Half-Dead who has seen the UnderVerse.
听着 我和这里的任何人没有联系
Look, I'm not with everyone here.
不过我有事情要跟他了结
But I will take a piece of him.
可以
A piece you will have.
制止他
Stop him!
伊尔根 我最强的手下
Irgun. One of my best.
如果你这样说
If you say so.
觉得这把刀怎么样？
What do you think of this blade?
后面重了半克
I think it's a half-gram heavy on the back end.
按我们的习惯
In our faith,
你可以保留你的战利品
you keep what you kill.
你认识我吗？
Are you familiar to me?
我们在某个遥远的地方见过？
Have we met on some distant field?
你认为我记得
You'd think I'd remember.
你认为我也记得
You'd think I would too.
带他见死亡修罗
Take him before the Quasi-Deads.
也许这个种畜会去的…
Perhaps the breeder would do it...
如果你邀请他
if somebody just asked him.
这可是难得的机会
It is a rare offer.
进入坟墓
A visit inside Necropolis.
很久没闻到这么美妙的味道了
It's been a long time since I smelled beautiful.
我给你带路
Let me show you the way.
漂亮的眼睛
Beautiful eyes.
来吧
Come.
六任马歇尔王称这里为家
The last six Lord Marshals have called this home.
很壮观 不是吗？
Magnificent, isn't it?
跟我以前见到的不一样 我们都是如此
I might have gone a different way. True of us all.
皈依者在接受死亡使者的标记
Converts receiving the mark of the Necromonger.
他们知道一种痛苦如何减轻另一种痛苦
They learn how one pain can lessen another.
这边
There now.
这个简直… 太完美了
That is just... perfect.
你越抗拒
The more you resist them,
造成的伤害就越大
the greater the damage will be.
一个新来的
A new one.
你给我们带来了这个
You've brought us the one.
有趣的种畜
Interesting breeder.
进入
Making entry.
不会太久的
This won't take long.
进入大脑皮层
We've entered his neocortex.
- 啊 瑞迪  - 退后
- Ahh! The Riddick!  - Regress.
扫描最新记忆
Scanning fresh memories.
一个叫做杰克的
Thoughts of someone called Jack.
瑞迪
Riddick!
她进了监狱
She went to prison.
发现一个元素族的人
Now we find thoughts of an Elemental.
可以阻挡死亡使者的种族
The one race that would slow the spread of Necromongers.
- 复仇星人  - 复仇星人
- Furyans.  - Furyans.
他从那里来？
Where does he come from?
是什么人？我想知道的是这些
Who are his people? These are the things I need to know.
我们发现了能量
We find energy.
你必须解决你的过去
You must settle your past.
我们发现了复仇星人的能量
We find Furyan energy.
- 为了我们大家  - 他是复仇星人
- For all of us.  - He's Furyan!
复仇星人
Furyan!
复仇星人幸存者
A Furyan survivor!
看看我们的星球 看看三十年前未能逃脱的人们的坟墓
Look at our world, at the graves of those who didn't escape 30 years ago.
除非能解决过去的事情 否则我们没有将来…
There is no future until we settle our past...
为了所有打着印记的人们
for all of us who bear the mark.
杀了复仇星人 杀了瑞迪
Kill the Furyan! Kill the Riddick!
杀了瑞迪 杀了瑞迪 杀了瑞迪
Kill the Riddick! Kill the Riddick! Kill the Riddick!
- 杀了瑞迪  - 杀了瑞迪
- Kill the Riddick!  - Kill the Riddick.
这个男人是谁？
Who is this man?
找到他 无论如何 找到他
Find him. Whatever it takes. Find him!
让我猜猜 这次是五个人
Let me guess. A five-man crew this time.
有些事情你可以做得更好的
Couple of things you could have done better.
首先 应该毁掉我飞船上藏着的追踪器
First, trash the locator beacon inside my ship... the one you jacked.
第二 也是非常重要的一点
And second... and this is really the more important part...
在你有机会的时候 应该杀了我
dust my dick when you get the chance.
- 还有什么问题吗？- 有
- Any questions?  - Yeah.
什么耽误了你这么长时间？
What took you so long?
走吧 大个子
Let's go, big boy.
进去出来 神不知鬼不觉 干得真漂亮
In and out, unsuspected and undetected. Damn, I love a good smash-and-grab.
别这么快 别这么快
Not so fast. Not so fast.
笨蛋 我们被发现了
Dickheads. We're pickin' up fields here.
船体被未知场发现
Unknown fields detected on hull.
- 我知道  来了  - 这是某种扫描场
- I knew it. Here it comes.  - This is some kind of scan.
不清楚 可能是探测到我们的热量
I don't know. Readin' our Btus, maybe?
- 发射伪装船  - 发射
- Let's drop one.  - Dropping.
伪装船发射
Decoy launched.
- 准备离子驱动  - 那么…
- Preparing to engage ion drive.  - So,
我们到哪把你丢下？
where do we drop your merc-killin' ass?
谁为你付赏金呢？
Who's gonna pay the most for you now?
- 屠夫湾  - 屠夫湾
- Butcher Bay?  - Butcher Bay.
每隔一天十分钟的放风时间
Ten minutes every other day on the dog run.
那里的蛋白质饼不错
Protein waffles aren't bad.
嘿 小熊星座怎么样？不错的小型双重戒备监狱
Hey, how 'bout Ursa Luna? Nice little double-max prison.
他们一直为我保留了一间 就等着我去
They keep a cell open for me... just in case I drop in.
你知道那些地方的问题吗？
You know the problem with these joints now?
对吃蛋白质饼的家伙来说 那简直是个健康俱乐部
Health clubs for waffle-eatin' pussies.
也许我们该想想 其它的地方玩游戏
Maybe we should think about uppin' our game here a little bit.
其它更可怕的地方
Think about someplace truly diabolical.
他到底在想什么？
What the hell is he thinkin' now?
他在想一个三重戒备的监狱
He's thinkin' a triple-maxprison.
没有阳光 整个星系只有三个星球…
A no-daylight slam. Only three of 'em left in this system...
其中两个太远
two of 'em outstay range for a shitty little under cutter
坐这条垃圾船永远也到不了
like this one with no legs.
只剩下一个…
Leavin' just... one...
烈焰星
Crematoria.
那正是你想的 是吗 托姆斯？
That is what you had in mind, right, Toombs?
嘿 他怎么知道我们要去的地方 而我们不知道？
Hey, how does he know where we're goin', and we don't?
他猜出来的
Dope it out.
- 我恨这次飞行  - 照做
- I hate this run.  - Just do it!
你不知道你的这些新船员
Don't know about this new crew of yours.
他们好像有点容易激动
They seem a bit skittish.
也许不应该告诉他们 你以前的船员怎么了
Probably shouldn't tell 'em what happened to the last crew.
瞧 也许你曾经是最好的杀手
You know, you supposed to be some slick-shit killer.
但瞧你现在…
Now look at you...
真糟糕
all back-of-the-bus and shit.
我说我们下一个攻击希里奥二号
I say we attack Helion Two next.
直接进攻他们的门户
Take it straight into their teeth.
需要二万人 五艘战舰 不会再多了 我保证
It'll cost you 20,000 heads, five warrior ships. Nothing more, I swear it.
尽管我喜欢强力攻击
While I do prize brute force,
但也许这种方法更巧妙
this approach is perhaps more artful.
从后面开始
Start at the end.
直接进攻希里奥五号
Go straight to Helion Five,
这个星系的最后一颗行星
the last planet in the system.
我们从暗面靠近
We approach from the night side.
先解决大炮
Remove these cannon first,
然后迅速攻击大型工事
then attack the larger placements at speed.
从后翼打败他们 十天…
We'll catch them on their rearflank. And in ten days'time,
其他行星上的人就会投降
the rest of those worlds will tumble before us.
看 和大多情况一样 盲点…
You see, as with most, their blind spot...
就在他们身后
is right behind them.
在星际附近发现离子飞行的痕迹
I've located an ion trail which leads off-world.
那你应该到星际 瓦寇
Then you should be off-world, Vaako.
我已经派了最好的追踪小组去了
I've deployed a tracker team. One of the best.
不管瑞迪在哪 找到他 干掉他
Wherever Riddick has gone, you lens him out and cleanse him.
你  你要我坐战舰去追一个种畜？
You. You want me to take a frigate for one breeder?
不要提问 瓦寇
Don't question it, Vaako!
接受命令
Take it on faith.
马歇尔王对你…
He's always been unsettled around you...
一直不放心
the Lord Marshal.
反复无常
Unsteady.
也许他知道他的一半 是像你这样武士
Perhaps because he knows he's half the warrior you are.
有人说他过于优雅了
Some say he's too artistic for the job.
我一点都不惊讶…
I wouldn't be surprised if someone promoted him soon...
如果有人加快他的死亡
to full dead.
小心你说的话
Take care what you say.
是不是应该说得轻一点？
Should I say it softly?
听起来更像阴谋？
So it sounds more like conspiracy?
哦 为什么一说到谁能继承王位
Oh, why is it that when anyone breathes about the demise of him on the throne...
就以为是在阴谋造反？
everyone assumes a conspiracy?
为什么这不是个明智的方案？
Why isn't that just prudent planning?
在他死前会任命一个继承者
When he is ready, he will name a successor.
谁？
Who?
托尔？斯卡尔斯？净化者？
Toal? Scales? The Purifier?
他们中没有一个有
None of them...
这样的力量与威严
with the strength, the dignity,
瓦寇王
of Lord Vaako.
你可以拥有你的战利品
You can keep what you kill.
- 住嘴  - 这就是死亡使者的法则
- Stop.  - That is the Necromancer way.
我说… 住嘴
I said... stop.
他的死亡会在适当的时候到来 不会提前一秒
His death will come in due time and not a moment sooner.
- 为什么？- 因为我为他服务 我们都为他服务 这叫做忠诚
- Why?  - Because I serve him. We all serve him. It's called fidelity.
这叫愚蠢
It's called stupidity.
喔 终于引起你的注意了
Well, finally some attention.
你如此伟大
You have such greatness in you.
只要你能像我一样看到它
If only you could see it like I do.
你知道我想要什么？
You know what I want?
今天我从背后悄无声息接近他 他还是发现了
Today I came up behind him in perfect silence and he knew.
我想进入坟墓
I wanna go down in Necropolis.
现在
Right now.
他半死的灵魂感觉到了我 他知道一切
His half-dead soul sensed I was behind him. He sees everything.
没有人看见
When no one is looking...
没有人在周围
when no one's around...
你坐在王位上…
I'm gonna get down on my knees...
我要跪在你的脚下
while you sit on the throne.
- 真没想到  - 元素族
- How unexpected.  - An Elemental.
- 在这里  - 我们的一个俘虏
- Here.  - One of the captives.
为什么 三十年后
And why, after 30 years,
是你？
should it be you?
但是 他并没有把她当做俘虏
He doesn't regard her as a captive, though.
元素族人 口头上说中立
Elementals... they talk of neutrality,
实际上都是巫师和间谍
but they're all witches and spies.
另外他们为什么都来去如风呢？
Why else would they come and go like the wind?
他去哪儿了？那个复仇星人现在躲在哪？
But where has he gone? Where is the Furyan hiding now?
你是个好武士
You be the good warrior.
去追瑞迪
Go after this Riddick.
我来查出为什么马歇尔王这么怕他
I'll find out why the Lord Marshal is so threatened by him.
你知道你睡觉磨牙吗？
Do you know you grind your teeth at night?
很性感
Sexy.
(火成星系 烈焰星)
目的地到达
Destination reached.
打开手动控制
Unlocking manual controls.
阳面700度
All right. I make 700 degrees on the day side,
阴面零下300度
300 below on the night side.
别被阳光晒到
Let's not get caught in the sun.
如果我同时拥有这个地方和地狱
If I owned this place and hell,
我会把这里出租出去 住在地狱
I'd rent this place out and live in hell.
- 蓝角… 很好  - 准备
- Blue angle... good.  - Stand by.
准备…
And...
角度正确
Plotted course good.
进入
Hit it!
降落角度 偏离
Angle of approach, not good.
瞧 不用手
Look, Ma. No hands!
减速器
Party poppers!
真厉害
I think I shit myself.
惊慌 托姆斯 太惊慌了
Skittish, Toombs. Very skittish.
舒服了？
Comfy?
旅途结束
When the ride's over,
你的墨镜就是我的了
your goggles are mine.
四人分帐
Four-way split!
29 4公里
29.4 kilometers.
这就是瑞迪
So, this is Riddick.
你他妈说什么 七十万？
What in the bowels of Christ are you talkin' about, 700K?
头 不要接这个活
Don't take this one, boss.
瞧 安纳托里已经感觉这是个麻烦
See? Anatoli here has a nose for trouble.
而这个家伙 瑞迪
And this one, this Riddick guy...
是个大 很大的麻烦
Big, big trouble.
所以 七十万不错了
So, 700,000 is good money.
托姆斯 是我就拿这笔钱
I'd take the money, Toombs.
组织每年为每个囚犯付我们看守费
The guild pays us a caretaker's fee for each prisoner each year.
我们付给赏金猎人 其预计寿命总费的20％
We pay mercs 20% of that total fee based on a certain life expectancy.
这个怎么样？
How's about this?
你把藏在控制台后的保险箱打开
You open that safe you got hidden behind the console there,
给我看账本 我来算该拿多少
show me the real books, then we figure out my cut.
然后走人
Then I'll be on my way.
看我的账本 这就是你的建议？
Open my books. This is what you suggest?
不是建议
Wasn't a suggestion.
如果你相信那些传言 最近可是很危险
These are dangerous days, if you believe the talk.
传言？关于死亡星球
Talk? About dead planets.
关于幽灵军团
About some ghost army.
关于他们
About them.
"他们"？
"Them"?
我要再点一下数字
I'll run the numbers again.
也许要几天
It takes a couple of days, probably,
你们可以留下来作客
so you can stay as my guest.
至少在这 我们是安全的
At least here, we are all safe.
- 是吗？- 是的 头
- Yes?  - Yes, boss.
我给你一天
I'll give it a day.
一天
One.
这里有囚犯…
There are inmates...
有罪犯
and there are convicts.
每个罪犯都有一个编号
A convict has a certain code.
要学会尊敬
And he knows to show a certain respect.
囚犯则相反
An inmate, on the other hand,
看守别人
pulls the pin on his fellow man.
担当守卫
Does the guards' work for them.
给这场游戏…
Brings shame...
带来耻辱
to the game.
那么 你想做哪个？
So, which are you gonna be?
我？
Me?
我只是路过
I'm just passin' through.
欢迎来到烈焰星
Welcome to Crematoria.
我应该从这个最佳位置捅进去吗？
Should I go for the sweet spot?
脊椎左边 第四节腰椎下面 腹部大动脉
Left of the spine, fourth lumbar down, the abdominal aorta.
血如泉涌
What a gusher.
我怎样才能有你这样的眼睛？
How do I get eyes like that?
你得杀一些人
You gotta kill a few people.
我杀过
Did that.
杀过很多
Did a lot of that.
那你应该被关起来
And then you gotta get sent to a slam.
一个永远见不到阳光的地方？
One where they tell you you'll never see daylight again?
这里没有医生能擦亮我的眼睛
Only there wasn't any doctor here who could shine my eyes,
即使有二十条库司烟
not even for 20 menthol Kools.
你说过的话有真的吗？
Was there anything you said that was true?
你打算怎么样？杀了我？
What are you gonna do, huh? Go for the sweet spot?
记住你在和谁说话 杰克
Remember who you're talkin' to, Jack.
杰克已经死了 她是弱者
Jack's dead. She was weak.
她不能坚持下去
She couldn't cut it.
我现在叫凯拉
The name's Kyra now.
我是只野兽
And I'm a new animal.
这可以是次很好的试验 可以…
They can be quite a test, these deep runs...
探测我们的内心
tests of our inner selves.
你认为呢？
Don't you find that true?
有人可以
Some men do.
离舰队还有段距离
Just being so far from the armada,
思想开始充满奇怪的想法 怀疑
the mind can start to fill with strange thoughts, doubts.
难道你从未怀疑过吗 瓦寇？
Don't you ever have doubts, Vaako?
- 怀疑？- 关于这场战争
- Doubts?  - About the campaign.
关于马歇尔王
About Lord Marshal.
首先并且一直 我是一个死亡使者的指挥官
First and always, I am a Necromonger commander.
所以 如果你是在考验我的忠诚 那么你只是考验了我的耐心
So if you're here to test my loyalty, you succeed only in testing my patience.
喔 不 不 那并不是我在这里的原因
Oh, no. No, that's not why I'm here at all.
我很高兴能占用你一会时间
I'm so glad I could steal you away for a moment.
没让你感到奇怪吗？
Doesn't it strike you odd?
现在的马歇尔王
Here we have the current Lord Marshal...
正在摧毁整个社会 但他却不能
destroying entire societies, and yet he can't bring himself...
杀掉一个不能反抗的元素族人
to kill one stranded Elemental.
为什么？
Why is that?
你不信仰我们的神
You don't pray to our god.
你不相信神 我听说
You pray to no god, I hear.
元素族人 我们预测
Elementals... we calculate.
不是我们
Don't we all.
但是现在 让我们首先开始做第一件事
But now let's have first things first.
- 瑞迪怎么了？- 说真的 我不知道他去了哪
- What of Riddick?  - In truth, I don't know where he went.
事实上 我更关心他从哪来
In truth, I'm more interested in where he came from.
当心你的脚下
Watch your step.
我一直都很好奇
I've always wondered,
元素族人能飞吗？
does an air Elemental fly?
现在 帮我一个忙
Now do me a favor.
预测一下你活着离开这个星球的可能性
Calculate the odds of you getting off this planet alive...
现在把它们切成两半
and now cut them in half.
不 我们飞不了
No, we can't fly.
但是我们擅长滑行
But we glide very well.
别威胁我 死亡使者
Save your threats, Necromonger.
我会告诉你想知道的瑞迪的情况的
I would have told you about Riddick for the asking.
它关系到一个预言 一个30多年以前的预言
It concerns a foretelling, a prediction now more than 30 years old.
一位年轻的勇士曾经问过一个预言家
A young warrior once consulteda seer.
预言家告诉他说一个出生在复仇星上的孩子 一个男孩
He was told a child would be born on the planet Furya... a male child...
有一天会打倒这个武士
who would someday cause the warrior's downfall.
让他在黑暗中死去
Cause his untimed death.
复仇星？复仇星是个被毁灭了的世界 没有生命存在
Furya? Furya's a ruined world. No life to speak of.
一个好的理由
For good reason.
这个年轻的武士进攻了复仇星
This young warrior mounted an attack on Furya,
杀掉他发现的所有年轻的男人
killing all young males he could find,
甚至用脐带扼死那些孩子
even strangling some with their birth cords.
一次彻底的打击 不是吗？
An artful stroke, wouldn't you say?
这个努力打破预言的武士 就是后来成为…
So this warrior, the one who tried to outwit the prediction, would later become...
这就是他为什么担心
That's why he worries.
马歇尔王
The Lord Marshal.
一个会让这个男人… 的孩子
Which would make the man-child...
他担心没有把男孩杀死在摇篮里
He worries he missed killing that child in its crib.
瑞迪
Riddick.
- 这就是对他如此重要的原因  - 等等
- That's why it's so vital to him.  - Wait.
- 是关于一个预言  - 等等 等等
- It's about a prophecy.  - Wait! Wait!
你在那吗？
Are you there?
你去实现马歇尔王的愿望
You do what your lord asks.
你要为他除掉瑞迪 这样做…
You cleanse Riddick for him, and in doing so...
可以证明你不朽的忠诚
you prove your undying loyalty.
或许最后他会放松警惕
And perhaps then he'll finally let down his guard.
还在这？
Still here, I See?
我在这已经18年了 看这个？
I've been here 18 years. See this?
我记得她是如此的漂亮 嗯 在灯光下会更动人
I remember how gorgeous she was. Well, gorgeous in a certain light.
现在 受到死亡诅咒的我
And now, for the goddamn death of me,
记不起她的名字
I cannot remember her name.
喂食时间到
Feeding time!
在这里度过我们的炼狱生活
We're here for the rest of our unnatural lives.
它们来了
Here they come!
无论你做什么 别看它们的眼睛
Whatever you do, don't make eye contact.
啊
Aaah!
这是动物语言
It's an animal thing.
搜她身 她总是在身上藏着刀
Check here for me. She's always got a blade somewhere.
哈
Hyah!
我想她不喜欢别人碰她
I don't think she likes being touched.
在你们能走的时候快走 否则准备受伤吧
I'd take my wounded and go while you still can.
你在这个地方有名字吗？
Is there a name for this private little world of yours, huh?
如果我们不跑会发生什么呢？
What happens there when we don't just run away?
用一只汤杯杀掉我们吗？
You'll kill us... with a soup cup?
实际上 是茶
Tea, actually.
什么？
What's that?
我会用茶杯杀死你们
I'll kill you with my teacup.
你知道规则 如果仍在名单上 就没有死
You know the rule. They aren't dead if they're still on the books.
嗯…
Mmm.
来啊
Come on.
用茶杯杀人
Death by teacup.
该死 为什么我没想到？
Damn. Why didn't I think of that?
我不是来玩"谁是最好的杀手？"
I didn't come to play "Who's the Better Killer?"
但这是我喜欢的游戏 你没听说吗？
But it's my favorite game. Haven't you heard?
- 我听说你来找我  - 就这些？
- I heard you came lookin' for me.  - Is that all?
你错过了精彩的部分
Then you missed the good part.
我被一些从天狼五号星来的 赏金猎人给盯上
Hooked up with some mercs outta Lupus Five.
他们把我带走 教我交易 给了我一把好刀
Said they'd take me on, teach me the trade, give me a good cut.
他们把我从奴隶中解救出来 瑞迪
They slaved me out, Riddick.
你知道在那个年纪里对于 你来说意味着什么吗？
Do you know what that could do to you when you're that age?
- 当你12岁的时候？- 我告诉你留在新麦加
- When you're 12 years old?  - I told you to stay in New Mecca.
你没听到吗？
Did you not listen?
赏金猎人都盯着我的脑袋
I had mercs on my neck.
以后也一直会盯着我的脑袋
I'll always have mercs on my neck.
我在一个冰冻星球呆了5年 只是为了让他们远离你
I spent five years on a frozen heap just to keep 'em away from you.
而你却离开那里加入了他们
And you go and sign up with the same fake badges...
他们会杀了你 并用你来做诱饵
that wanted to cut you up and use you for bait.
你指什么 瑞迪？你干的就是对的吗？
What are you pitching, Riddick? That you cutting' out was a good thing?
你在我的掩护下穿过宇宙
That you had my ass covered from halfway across the universe?
你和赏金猎人签约
You signed with mercs.
当时我身边没有任何人
There was nobody else around.
打开盖子 呼吸点新鲜空气
Let's pop the cork. Get some fresh air.
他们去了顶层…
So they do go topside...
去换空气去了
to swap out air.
有意思
Interesting.
你到底是谁？
Who the hell are you?
一旦它发生了 它会发生的很快
When it happens, it'll happen fast.
在我切断栅栏的时候 呆在我后面或者呆在这里
Stay on my leg when I cut fence or stay here...
度过你平凡的生命
for the rest of your natural life.
没人能离开这里 没人
Nobody outs this place. Nobody.
他不是别人
He ain't "nobody."
首先是好消息 让我和这里的朋友讨论一些事情
Good news first. Talked things over with my amigos here.
我们杀掉你们将可以得到七十七万五千
We'll cut you in for 775K.
那好吧
Well, all right.
坏消息是什么？他们关掉了这里的妓院？
What's the bad news? They close the local whorehouse?
不 比那要坏 坏的多
No. The bad news is worse than that. Much worse.
我们的驾驶员看到了这个 它越过了这条航线
Our pilot, he saw this. It crossed a shipping lane.
你们知道这个是什么吗？
Any idea what this might be?
从没看过这个
Never saw nothing' like it.
这艘飞船是回希里奥 帕莱姆的
This ship charts back to Helion Prime.
你们知道 安纳托里有一个能发现麻烦的鼻子
You know, Anatoli's got a nose for trouble,
他认为麻烦会跟着你们到这里
and he thinks trouble follows you here.
听着 我们清除了我们的踪迹 到这个鬼地方
Look. We dusted our tracks and got the hell outta there.
不可能我们没有甩掉他们
There is no way we didn't lose them.
他们？
"Them"?
这是我的囚犯 我的
This is my prisoner. Mine.
不是别人的
Nobody else's.
现在我要我的钱
And I want my money now.
那么…
So...
你偷走了一个囚犯…
you stole a prisoner...
从他们那里？
from "them"?
不
No.
瑞迪 不
Riddick. No!
你应该带走这些钱的 托姆斯
Should taken the money, Toombs.
你要杀我吗？
You gonna kill me?
赏金猎人
Mercs.
这儿有一些警卫 但不可能是所有的
Some guards here, but this can't be all of them.
到后面去检查一下他们的船舱 要小心些
Check their slots in the back... and be careful.
不用麻烦了
Don't bother.
警卫们不在这儿
Guards ain't there.
他们发现死亡使者来这里找我
They figured out the Necros are coming for me.
他们计划拿走所有的钱 干掉赏金猎人
Plan was to clean the bank, ghost the mercs,
穿过隧道
break wide through the tunnel.
然后有人拿这个火箭发射器 在这里开了一炮
And then somebody got a lucky shot off with this rocket launcher here...
然后拿走了这个橇
and took out the sled.
警卫们步行离开 但是破坏了门锁 因此没人能够跟上他们
Guards took off on foot but rigged the door so no one could follow.
他们要从机棚里弄一架飞船 留下这里的其他人等死
They'll take the one ship in the hangar and leave everyone else here to die.
你怎么知道这些事？
How come you know all this shit?
你当时并不在这儿
You weren't even here.
因为这本来就是我的计划
'Cause it was my plan.
我真该带走这些钱的
I should taken the money.
瑞迪
Riddick!
这是什么？他在想什么？
What is this? What is he thinking?
- 一旦太阳出来  - 我们只能坚持5分钟
- Once that sun comes up...  - We'll last five minutes.
5分钟 我们在外面不可能坚持过30秒
Five minutes. We ain't gonna last 30 seconds out there.
它会把我们像火柴一样点燃
It'll light you up like a match.
20英里的缓冲区域 30公里到机棚
20-mile buffer zone and 30 klicks to the hangar.
在那样的地形上走30公里？
30 klicks over that terrain?
它正在朝正确的方向移动 我们能做到的
It's moving in the right direction. We could make it.
躲在阴暗处
Stay behind the night,
在太阳出来之前
ahead of the sun.
那要达到一定的速度
There's gonna be one speed...
我的速度
mine.
如果你不能跟上 就别靠近
If you can't keep up, don't step up.
你会死的
You'll just die.
瑞迪？
Riddick?
快 快 上去 快上去 从这爬上去
Go, go! Go on! Go! Climb here!
快爬 快 快
Climb! Go! Go, go, go!
头儿
Boss!
在上面
Up there.
- 过来看看  - 因为安纳托里这样说？
- Take a look.  - Because Anatoli says so?
因为他的鼻子这样说
Because his nose says so.
这上面什么都没有
There's nothing' up here.
喔
Oh, shit.
瑞迪
Riddick.
他们正向火山区域前进 他们打算弄走我们的飞船
They're heading right for the volcano fields. They're going for our ship!
他们不可能先到机棚 不可能
No chance do they get to the hangar first. No chance!
下一个 下一个洞口 我们要在那里抓住他们
Next one! Next hole! We'll catch 'em there!
不会再让你们跑了
No more run for you.
那家伙去哪了？
Where did the big guy go?
哦
Ohh...
关上它
Close it!
你那是干什么？你不关心你的死活吗？
What was that? You don't care if you live or die?
假如我先杀了他们 就无所谓
If I kill them first, not really.
或许我会
Maybe I do.
接着跑
Keep moving!
凯拉？
Kyra?
- 凯拉  - 什么？
- Kyra!  - What?
给我快点
Get that ass moving!
瑞迪？
Riddick?
记得我说过不在乎死活吗？
Remember what I said about not caring if I lived or died?
你知道我是开玩笑的 对吗？
You knew I was kidding, right?
一定的速度
"One speed."
温度异常
Temperature differential.
你的绳子
Your rope.
太晚了 我们从来都没有想过会成功
It's too late. We're never gonna make it.
你的绳子 给我你的绳子
Your rope! Gimme your rope!
你的水 所有的水
And your water. All of it!
躲在山的阴暗处 别等我 快跑
Stay in the shadow of the mountain. Don't wait for me. Run!
瑞迪
Riddick!
啊
Aaah!
该死的机棚在哪？
Where the hell is that hangar?
在那
There it is.
听
Listen.
让我猜猜 死亡使者
Let me guess. Necros.
还有很多火力
And a whole lotta Necro firepower.
该死 真恨自己不是坏人
Shit! I hate not being the bad guys.
在太阳重新追上我们烧掉整个山谷之前
I figure we got three minutes
我们还有3分钟
before the sun hits us again, burns out this whole valley.
- 等等  - 我们干还是不干？
- Wait.  - We gonna do this or not?
再等等
Just wait.
艾伦
Ellen.
她的名字叫艾伦 我从来不曾真的忘记她的名字
Her name was Ellen. I never really forgot.
啊 头
Aaah! Boss!
- 记得你喜欢的游戏吗？- "谁是最好的杀手"？
- Remember that favorite game of yours?  - "Who's the Better Killer?"
- 我们开始吧  - 上
- Let's play.  - Come on!
右边
On the right!
小心 你后面
Watch out! Behind you!
凯拉
Kyra!
塞跋
Sybar!
不
No!
啊
Aaah!
起来 起来
Get up. Get up!
快起来
Please get up.
现在
So,
你可以求饶了
you can kneel.
我想你现在知道了
I think you know now.
我想你知道谁毁灭了复仇星
I think you know who tore Furya apart.
这个印记充满了整个民族的愤怒
This mark carries the anger of an entire race.
但是这会带来痛苦
But it's going to hurt.
凯拉？
Kyra?
我应该告诉你一个消息
I was supposed to deliver a message to you...
如果瓦寇不能杀掉你
if Vaako failed to kill you.
一个来自马歇尔王的消息
A message from the Lord Marshal himself.
他要你离开希里奥 离开他
He tells you to stay away from Helion, stay away from him,
作为报酬 你不会再被追杀了
and in return, you'll be hunted no more.
但是瓦寇很可能会说你死了
But Vaako will most likely report you as dead.
所以这就是你的机会
So this is your chance.
去做别人从未成功过的事
Your chance to do what no man has ever done.
那个女孩
The girl.
他们要把她带去哪里？
Where will they take her?
一些事情 我们都开始了…
We all began... as something else.
我已经做了… 不可思议的事情…
I've done... unbelievable things...
以信仰起誓 那从来都不是我自己
in the name of a faith that was never my own.
他会像对待我这样去对待她
And he'll do to her what he did to me.
作为死亡使者我警告你别回去
The Necromonger in me warns you not to go back.
作为复仇星人
But the Furyan in me...
希望不要听这些
hopes you won't listen.
神知道… 我曾经梦见过它
God knows... I've dreamed of it.
(希里奥 帕莱姆星)
我失去了一个净化者
I have lost a Purifier...
但是在众多的指挥官中又得到了一个
but I have gained a first among commanders.
有点迟了 不是吗
It is overdue, isn't it...
我们都知道你的功勋卓著
that we acknowledge your many accomplishments,
你坚定不移的信仰
your steady faith,
最重要的是你永远的忠诚
and above all, your unflinching loyalty.
绝对服从 忠诚直到暗黑星际来临
Obedience without question. Loyalty till UnderVerse come.
做的好 瓦寇
Well done, Vaako.
这是其中的一天
This is a day of days.
高兴起来 瓦寇
Look more pleased, Vaako.
你已经消灭了他的敌人
You have killed his enemy...
还有他的疑心
and his suspicions.
我应该把他的头带回来
I should have brought back his head.
你看见他没有了呼吸 你看见他死在地上
You saw him unbreathing. You saw him dead on the ground.
瑞迪不是普通的人 一眨眼的时间就杀死了我20个人
Riddick was no common breeder. In a heartbeat he dropped 20 of my men.
所有的神话都不是奇迹 甚至不存在宗教里
All mysteries are not miracles, not even in this religion.
如果你说它存在 那么它就存在
And if you say it is certain, then it is certain,
我们已经准备那样说了 是吗？
and we've already said it, haven't we?
是的
We have.
现在 告诉我这是否是真的
Now, tell me if it's true.
告诉我那个复仇星人已经死了
Tell me the Furyan is gone,
那么我就可以结束这场战争 不再听到他的声音
and I can close this campaign without hearing his boot steps.
如果他死了
If he is dead,
我感觉我离他那样的命运也不远了
I sense I'm not far from the same fate,
对你已经没有用了
being of no further use here.
我应该告诉你瑞迪还活着吗？
Shouldn't I tell you that Riddick is still alive?
别激我 艾尔伦
Don't try me, Aereon.
我可以让你和其他希里奥 帕莱姆人一起去做苦力
I could plow you under with the rest of Helion Prime.
没有人真正知道将来会怎样
No one really knows the future.
那么告诉我瓦寇成功的可能性
Then tell me the odds that Vaako met with success,
我会成为…
that I will now be the one...
带领人民进入暗黑星际的王者
who can carry his people across the threshold into UnderVerse,
在那里他们开始真正的生活
where they shall begin true life.
告诉我我想听的 艾尔伦
Tell me what I want to hear, Aereon,
或许我会挽救你的家园… 最后
and maybe I'll save your home world... for last.
- 有这个可能性  - 哪个？
- The odds are good...  - That?
你将到达暗黑星际
That you will reach the UnderVerse...
很快
soon.
飞船上升
Ascension protocol!
我们仍然有很多人在外面 马歇尔王 地面部队 侦察飞船
We still have numbers out there, Lord Marshal... sweep teams, recon ships.
他们没有时间赶回来
They would be hard-pressed to make it back...
让我的舰队离开地面
Get my armada off the ground!
- 你是说在希里奥  - 我是说在这里 这艘飞船上
- You mean on Helion?  - I mean here, on this very ship!
你是不是看错了？因为害怕而眼花了
Could you be wrong? Mind fabricates fear.
- 你是不是看错了？- 没你错的厉害 你还让他活着
- Could you be wrong?  - Not so wrong as you when you left him alive!
同样的错误你犯了两次
It's twice a mistake.
现在不仅仅是失败 而且是继位失败
Not only your failure, but now the report of success.
我们该怎么弥补这个过错？该怎么做？
How do we salvage this? How? How?
应该让马歇尔王知道这些
Lord Marshal's got to be warned.
那你将永远看不到暗黑星际
You will never see the UnderVerse!
他会很快杀了我们两个的
He will kill us both before our due time.
我认为应该给瑞迪一个机会
I say give Riddick his chance.
如果他真如你所说的那么厉害
If he is half of what you think,
他至少能够让马歇尔王受伤
he can at least wound the Lord Marshal...
那就是我们必须行动的时候了
and that is when you must act.
仅仅是取代他？仅仅是杀了他？
Just to take his place? Just to keep what I kill?
- 那是死亡使者的命运  - 这还不够
- That is the Necromonger way.  - It is not enough!
那么为了你的信仰去吧
Then you do it for the faith!
如果他害怕了 他就变弱了
If he has fear, he has weakness.
如果他变弱了 瓦寇
If he has weakness, Vaako...
他就不应该继续统治下去了
He is unworthy of lordship.
这样做是为了所有的死亡使者
We do it for all Necromongers.
坚守信仰
Protect the faith.
这仍然可以是历史的一页
This can still be a day of days,
但是时机
but the timing...
必须恰到好处
must be flawless.
最终形态 执行我的命令
Final protocol. Execute on my order.
进去
Go inside.
他们现在离开吗？
Are they leaving now?
西扎 进去
Ziza! Go inside!
我们发现这个影像兵死了
We found this Lensor dead.
给我看看他最后的影像
Show me his last sight.
托尔指挥官
Commander Toal.
他不会逃走两次的
He won't escape twice.
别动
Stay your weapons!
他是来找我的
He came for me.
想一下
Consider this:
如果你现在在这里倒下了
If you fall here now,
你永远都站不起来
you'll never rise.
但是如果你选择另外一种方式
But if you choose another way...
死亡使者的方式
the Necromonger way...
你会在某时死去
you'll die in due time...
在暗黑星际里重新复活
and rise again in the UnderVerse.
去他那
Go to him.
你会感到痛苦
It hurts...
开始的时候
at first.
但是一会过后 痛苦会消失 就像他们说的那样
But after a while, the pain goes away, just as they promise.
- 你和我在一起吗 凯拉？- 有一瞬间
- Are you with me, Kyra?  - There's a moment...
你几乎能从他的眼里看到暗黑星际的时候
when you can almost see the UnderVerse through his eyes.
它看上去是那么的完美
It makes it sound perfect...
一个每个人都能够重新开始的地方
a place where anyone can start over.
你和我在一起吗 凯拉？
Are you with me, Kyra?
现在转化…
Convert now...
还是永远的倒下
or fall forever.
你杀掉了我所有的东西
You killed everything I know.
瓦寇
Vaako.
还没到时候
Not yet.
我已经很长时间没看到自己流血了
Been a long time since I've seen my own blood.
这是他最后的时刻
These are his last moments.
给我你的灵魂
Give me your soul.
他妈的
Fuck you!
你杀不了我的
You're not the one to bring me down.
现在 在他受伤的时候杀了那头野兽
Now! Kill the beast while he's wounded!
帮帮我 瓦寇 杀了他
Help me, Vaako. Kill him.
瓦寇？
Vaako?
原谅我
Forgive me.
恰到好处
Flawless.
不
No.
No-o-o!
现在会怎样呢？
Now what would be the odds of that?
我以为你已经死了
I thought you were dead.
你和我在一起吗 凯拉？
Are you with me, Kyra?
我一直都和你在一起
I was always with you.
早在一起了
I was.
这是收获的战利品
You keep what you kill.